<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="../teiHeader.xml"/>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="page" n="124">
        <pb n="124"/>
        <lg xml:id="block_A" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2Fec9451f2-4119-4754-ba44-85fb24e64400.jp2/382,851,3576,2137/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>WE ENTER THIS SANCTUARY to welcome Shabbat.</l>
          <l>Within these walls we sit surrounded by numberless generations.</l>
          <l>Our ancestors built the synagogue as a visible sign of God&apos;s Presence in their midst.</l>
          <l>Throughout our long history and our endless wanderings, it has endured,</l>
          <l>a beacon of truth, love, and justice for all humanity.</l>
          <l>Its presence guided our ancestors to lives of righteousness,</l>
          <l>holding up to them a vision of their truest selves.</l>
          <l>Now we, in our turn, come into this sanctuary to affirm the sacredness of our lives.</l>
          <l>May we enter this place in peace.</l>
          <l>May holiness wrap around us as we cross its threshold.</l>
          <l>Weariness, doubt, the flaws within our human hearts,</l>
          <l>the harshness of the week - let these drop away at the door.</l>
          <l>In the brightness of Shabbat, let peace settle upon us as we lift our hearts in prayer.</l>
        </lg>
        <lg xml:id="block_B" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2Fec9451f2-4119-4754-ba44-85fb24e64400.jp2/395,3291,2923,2248/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>MAY THE DOOR of this synagogue be wide enough</l>
          <l>to receive all who hunger for love, all who are lonely for friendship.</l>
          <l>May it welcome all who have cares to unburden,</l>
          <l>thanks to express, hopes to nurture.</l>
          <l>May the door of this synagogue be narrow enough</l>
          <l>to shut out pettiness and pride, envy and enmity.</l>
          <l>May its threshold be no stumbling block</l>
          <l>to young or straying feet.</l>
          <l>May it be too high to admit complacency,</l>
          <l>selfishness and harshness.</l>
          <l>May this synagogue be, for all who enter,</l>
          <l>the doorway to a richer and more meaningful life.</l>
        </lg>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>