<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="../teiHeader.xml"/>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="page" n="167">
        <pb n="167"/>
        <lg xml:id="block_A" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2F99251a86-0084-4aa4-8345-2c64f93b2bba.jp2/1359,526,2679,3981/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>SOME PERISHED by fire, some by water.</l>
          <l>Some crossed the sea, or watered the desert.</l>
          <l>Some starved all week to make a Shabbat feast.</l>
          <l>Some were left childless until old age.</l>
          <l>Some lifted their chins beneath a father&apos;s knife.</l>
          <l>Those who came before us gave everything</l>
          <l>so that we, generations later, could glorify You.</l>
          <l>And despite the dangers, with Your protection,</l>
          <l>some did survive, and even flourished,</l>
          <l>some reaped in joy, were spared the knife,</l>
          <l>were granted children.</l>
          <l>We are their inheritors, O God,</l>
          <l>and we know how rare is our good fortune</l>
          <l>to be born to such hard-won treasures.</l>
          <l>A great responsibility is ours,</l>
          <l>and Yours as well,</l>
          <l>for if You do not sustain us,</l>
          <l>as you did Abraham and Sarah,</l>
          <l>Rebecca and Isaac, Jacob, Rachel and Leah,</l>
          <l>then who will sing Your praises?</l>
          <l>Who will lift their chins, as we do now,</l>
          <l>to sanctify Your name?</l>
          <l>בָּרוּךְ אַתָּה, יְיָ, פּוֹקֵד שָׂרָה וּמָגֵן אַבְרָהָם.</l>
          <l>Baruch atah, Adonai, pokeid Sarah u&apos;magein Avraham.</l>
        </lg>
        <lg xml:id="block_B" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2F99251a86-0084-4aa4-8345-2c64f93b2bba.jp2/896,5018,3736,1255/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>... The word of Adonai came to Abram in a vision, saying: &apos;Fear not, Abram, I am a shield to</l>
          <l>you and your reward shall be very great . . . Look to the heaven and count the stars. . . So shall</l>
          <l>your offspring be.&apos; And because he put his trust in God, God reckoned it to his merit.&quot;</l>
          <l>Genesis 15:1, 5, 6</l>
          <l>In difficult moments of our lives we turn to God to help and sustain us. The classic chatimah</l>
          <l>(conclusion) to the Avot/Imahot prayer evokes God as &quot;Abraham&apos;s shield.&quot; In this egalitarian</l>
          <l>version we evoke Genesis 21:1 where God takes note of Sarah (TP pokeid) as she struggles with</l>
          <l>infertility. The chatimah, as with the rest of the prayer, indicates that each of us experiences God</l>
          <l>differently.</l>
        </lg>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>