<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="../teiHeader.xml"/>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="page" n="vii">
        <pb n="vii"/>
        <lg xml:id="block_A" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2F0140bfac-5d2e-4f38-a2b6-4001c4a63cfa.jp2/901,347,3768,5870/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>Introduction</l>
          <l>While prayer invites us to beseech God, we must also be open to what God wants</l>
          <l>from us. Samuel Karff wrote, “Each generation must struggle to hear the call, &apos;Where</l>
          <l>art thou?&apos; Each must choose to answer, &apos;Here I am, send me.&quot;&quot; Each generation</l>
          <l>merely each individual. A siddur must challenge narcissism; that challenge begins by</l>
          <l>saying to a worshipper: your voice is here amidst others. To hear the call: to realize</l>
          <l>that prayer is not merely an outpouring of self; it is the opening of our senses to what</l>
          <l>is beyond our selves. Send me: prayer must motivate us to give selflessly.</l>
          <l>-</l>
          <l>In any worship setting, people have diverse beliefs. The challenge of a single liturgy is</l>
          <l>to be not only multi-vocal, but poly-vocal — to invite full participation at once,</l>
          <l>without conflicting with the keva text. (First, the keva text must be one that is</l>
          <l>acceptable; hence, the ongoing adaptations of certain prayers, over time, such as the</l>
          <l>Gvurot.) Jewish prayer invites interpretation; the left hand material was selected both</l>
          <l>for metaphor and theological diversity. The choices were informed by the themes of</l>
          <l>Reform Judaism and Life: social justice, feminism, Zionism, distinctiveness, human</l>
          <l>challenges. The heritage of Reform brings gems from the Union Prayer Book and from</l>
          <l>Gates of Prayer, as well as from Reform&apos;s great literary figures over the last century</l>
          <l>and</l>
          <l>more.</l>
          <l>Theologically, the liturgy needs to include many perceptions of God: the transcen-</l>
          <l>dent, the naturalist, the mysterious, the partner, the evolving God. In any given</l>
          <l>module of prayer, e.g., the Shma and Its Blessings, we should sense all of these ways.</l>
          <l>The distinction of an integrated theology is not that one looks to each page to find</l>
          <l>one&apos;s particular voice, but that over the course of praying, many voices are heard, and</l>
          <l>ultimately come together as one. The ethic of inclusivity means awareness of and</l>
          <l>obligation to others rather than mere self-fulfillment.</l>
          <l>An integrated theology communicates that the community is greater than the sum of</l>
          <l>its</l>
          <l>parts. While individuals matter deeply, particularly in the sense of our emotional</l>
          <l>and spiritual needs and in the certainty that we are not invisible, that security should</l>
          <l>be a stepping stone to the higher value of community, privilege and obligation. We</l>
          <l>join together in prayer because together, we are stronger and more apt to commit to</l>
          <l>the values of our heritage. Abraham knew that just ten people made a difference. In</l>
          <l>worship, all should be reminded of the social imperatives of community.</l>
          <l>Prayer must move us beyond ourselves. Prayer should not reflect &quot;me&quot;; prayer should</l>
          <l>reflect our values and ideals. God is not in our image; we are in God&apos;s. It is critical that</l>
          <l>Reform Jews understand what is expected of them. The diverse theologies of the new</l>
          <l>siddur include religious naturalism, the theology of human adequacy, process theology,</l>
        </lg>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>