<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="../teiHeader.xml"/>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="page" n="viii">
        <pb n="viii"/>
        <lg xml:id="block_A" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2Ff0955823-ef73-4281-89c9-9fc6e4d05ca7.jp2/402,429,3640,5466/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>and the balance of particularism and universalism. But the essence of Reform liturgy</l>
          <l>continues to be what God demands of us, with heavy emphasis on ethical action and</l>
          <l>social justice.</l>
          <l>In Beyond the Worship Wars, Thomas G. Long teaches, &quot;Part of the joy of worship is to</l>
          <l>know the motions, know the words, know the song. The vital congregations knew</l>
          <l>their order of worship and moved through it with deep familiarity. What is more, the</l>
          <l>worshippers had active roles - speaking, singing, moving and many of these they</l>
          <l>could perform from memory.&quot; The siddur is a tool in the larger system of worship.</l>
          <l>Lawrence Hoffman teaches, &quot;The book is less text than pre-text for the staging of an</l>
          <l>experience. We are returning to the age of orality, where performance of prayer</l>
          <l>matters more than the fixed words. The question of worship leadership has expanded</l>
          <l>now, to include the theology and artistry of being a shliach tzibur - how to</l>
          <l>orchestrate seating, fill empty space, provide the right acoustics, and honor</l>
          <l>individualism within the group experience.&quot;</l>
          <l>Using Mishkan T&apos;filah, the actual selection of prayer can wait for the moment. The</l>
          <l>sh&apos;liach tzibur must offer a recipe that works comfortably for the community, and be</l>
          <l>able to adapt each week to the particular needs of the community, and to individuals</l>
          <l>within that community.</l>
          <l>Mishkan T&apos;filah invites familiarity, even as it allows for diversity. Over time, one</l>
          <l>cannot help but memorize the book. The content of each page spread, though varied,</l>
          <l>becomes known. The constancy of the keva text (the right hand side of each page</l>
          <l>which offers the traditional prayer) anchors every creative prayer on the left. It is the</l>
          <l>cumulative effect of worshipping from this siddur that will deepen meaningful ritual.</l>
          <l>The publication of Mishkan T&apos;filah continues the Reform movement&apos;s tradition of</l>
          <l>liturgical innovation. A single prayer book provides an important vehicle for group</l>
          <l>identification as well as personal prayer. The Union Prayer Book and its successor Gates</l>
          <l>of Prayer and now Mishkan T&apos;filah each expresses the ethos and values of its own era,</l>
          <l>at the same time being fully rooted in the structure and substance of the historical</l>
          <l>liturgical tradition of the Jewish people.</l>
          <l>The title Mishkan T&apos;filah is drawn from Exodus 25:8 where God commands us to</l>
          <l>build a portable sanctuary that can accompany us on our wanderings. “And let them</l>
          <l>build Me a sanctuary that I may dwell among them.&quot; Mishkan T&apos;filah is a dwelling</l>
          <l>place for</l>
          <l>prayer, one that moves with us wherever we might be physically or</l>
          <l>spiritually. It offers the opportunity for God, the individual and community to meet.</l>
        </lg>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>