<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <xi:include href="../teiHeader.xml"/>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="page" n="xv">
        <pb n="xv"/>
        <lg xml:id="block_A" xml:lang="en" facs="https://momoiro.hallyu.io/mishkan/iiif/3/mishkan%2F1cbdcd6e-7af0-4207-9a50-df3e11620bbf.jp2/885,272,3716,5818/max/0/default.jpg">
          <l>A Note on Style and Usage</l>
          <l>Mishkan T&apos;filah offers many opportunities for diverse usage and worship styles. Most</l>
          <l>of the prayers in this siddur are set as a two-page spread, with the keva (primary,</l>
          <l>traditional) liturgy on the right-hand page and alternative prayer choices on the left-</l>
          <l>hand side. The right-hand Hebrew text is accompanied by a faithful translation, and</l>
          <l>transliteration; the left-hand page contains poetry, prayers and kavanot (meditations)</l>
          <l>thematically tied to the keva text but reflecting diverse theological points of view.</l>
          <l>Layouts of the prayers invite different usage. Some passages are set to facilitate</l>
          <l>responsive readings, though all passages allow for unison offering. It is suggested that</l>
          <l>the community vary its vocal expression in prayer, with quieter or more exuberant</l>
          <l>tones at appropriate moments, as guided by the worship leader.</l>
          <l>The two-page spreads are intended so that only one prayer per page spread is read,</l>
          <l>either in Hebrew or English. Once that single piece is prayed, the worshipper turns the</l>
          <l>page. Thus pages need be announced only when they are skipped. (These simple</l>
          <l>instructions at the beginning of each service will guide new worshippers.) If the</l>
          <l>worship leader begins each prayer slowly, this will help worshippers to locate their</l>
          <l>places easily.</l>
          <l>A linear-style service option is offered in Service II for Friday night and Shabbat</l>
          <l>morning. Linear pages are designed with a blue frame around the page. The English in</l>
          <l>these services is not a direct translation of the Hebrew prayers.</l>
          <l>To pray the most traditional liturgy, one would use the right-hand side of the two-</l>
          <l>page spread of any service (except Services II).</l>
          <l>&quot;Stage directions&quot; and choreography such as when to stand or sit are minimized for</l>
          <l>maximum flexibility and with respect for varying congregational customs.</l>
          <l>Spiritual commentaries, notes on rabbinic practices, and source citations span the</l>
          <l>bottom of the pages, below the liturgical frame. The heading &quot;For those who choose&quot;</l>
          <l>refers to Jewish customs established by long usage. While not binding, many</l>
          <l>congregants will find them meaningful, and their use can enhance one&apos;s kavanah. Text</l>
          <l>sources are abbreviated: M. Shabbat 2:1 is read as Mishnah Shabbat, chapter 2,</l>
          <l>paragraph 1. Shabbat 2b-3a refers to the Talmud tractate Shabbat, page 2b to page 3a.</l>
          <l>Rubric headings are on the outside margins, indicating the current prayer&apos;s place</l>
          <l>within the service.</l>
        </lg>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>